Fabio Battaglia

Born in Italy, 22-Sep-1990 6 Cromwell Mansions, King Street, London, UK W69JX

□ (+44) 750 383 1291 · (+39) 340 381 35 42 | 🗷 fabio.battaglia90@gmail.com | 🖸 farbiondriven | 📓 farbiondriven | 🗖 fabiobattaglia90

Summary_

Software Engineer with experience on high availability systems for Biometric Security and Travel Industry. I currently work as a Lead Software Engineer for Remark AI, a biometric system application provider, in London. I'm result oriented, I have good interpersonal and organizational skills, I'm proactive and capable of working effectively with no supervision. I regularly contribute over the stack exchange community and on Github.

Work Experience

Remark Al London, United Kingdom

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2020 - present

- Design and development of a system for thermal scanning, mask wearing recognition and face recognition using thermal or basic network
- Development of Microservices using Python, C++, MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, Kafka, Traefik, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD Pipelines deploying in AWS or on-premise installations.
- Implemented RTSP re-streaming server using Gstreamer to stream local files to RTSP

Amadeus London, United Kingdom

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- Development of server applications using C++ 11;
- · Coordination for a proof of concept to use Drools management system to develop a new application, using Java, Openshift, Mongodb;
- · Mentoring of junior members and interns, giving supervision and project planning for dedicated projects

XiD Technologies Singapore

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2015 - Aug. 2017

- · Design and Development of applications connecting 3rd party devices performing Face and Fingerprint recognition to XiD FaaS system, integrating Hanvon, ZK, Suprema with custom Business requirements;
- · Integrated Fingerpint and RFID Security System and CCTV for Changi Airport Terminal 5 construction, providing real-time screen alerts, antipassback, WP expiration functionalities;
- Algorithm design using MATLAB for testing and C/C++ for development. Main techniques used are HAAR detection, ASM and histogram-based
- Development of Embedded Software and Overview of Hardware Architecture for XiD Revo Face 1.0 and Design of a fully in-house made 1.5 version using ARM 9 based architecture, controlling LCD screen, EM, Mifare RFID readers, Custom illumination, Custom Camera mount;
- · Moved to an architecture using purely off-the-shelf components using 3rd party RTSP network cameras, illumination and actuation. I designed and developed an orchestrator collecting the datastream to our Face Recognition algorithm, managing all devices and connecting to our customer database; the system was developed using C#, using C# bindings for C++ libraries;
- · Design and Development of an Android based application using a custom-made device, to capture attendance and perform verification of employees using Fingerprint and RFID card, using Android Studio, Java, MySQL.

ENFA Rome, Italy

CONTROL SYSTEMS ENGINEER INTERNSHIP

Jun. 2014 - Oct. 2014

• In the context of research for Nuclear fusion technologies, the project's goal was to identify and characterize the behaviour of a Tokamak liquid lithium limiter, using an infrared thermal camera. Using MATLAB and C++ a real-time tool was built to monitor the heat distribution on the liquid limiter. After post-processing, a mathematical model of the heat distribution on the limiter was defined;

High School Concetto Marchesi

ROBOTICS TEACHER

Catania, Italy Mar. 2014 - Jun. 2014

• Teaching as a Robotics Expert to a class of 20 High School students for an afternoon class, project financed by EU PON;

- · Theory lessons covering basic concepts of Robotics, Electronics, Programming, Cinematics, Control systems; · Hands-on sessions building an auto-orientating PTZ camera using Arduino, Servomotors, light sensors and a webcam;
- Building a mobile 2 wheels robot self oriented using light sensors for obstacle avoidance;

Education

College of Europe Bruges, Belgium

ADVANCED MASTER ON EUROPEAN UNION LAW (LL.M)

Sept. 2017 - June. 2018

- Beneficiary of the excellence-based ENP Scholarship
- Thesis: "Human rights clauses in the EU'S International agreements, with focus on the Association Agreements in the Eastern neighbourhood". Supervisor: M. Maresceau
- Attending intensive course "EU State Aid Law", held by Prof. M. Merola

Università degli Studi Roma Tre

Rome, Italy

FULL DEGREE IN LAW (JD EQUIVALENT)

Oct. 2009 - Sept. 2016

• Final Mark: 110/110 cum laude with special mention

Université Paris 1 Panthéon-Sorbonne

Paris, France

RESEARCH THESIS ABROAD

May 2016 - July 2016

- Thesis: Le contrôl juridictionnel sur les décisions de sanction des autorités administratives indépendantes: vers un modèle commun européen
- Supervisors: Prof. G. Rossi, Prof. E. Cardi, Prof. D. Capitant

Université Paris Descartes Paris, France

EXCHANGE PROGRAM

Oct. 2011 - June 2012

• Eight exams passed with distinctioned related to EU law, International Law, Civil Law

University of Malta Msida, Malta

Exchange Program Sept. 2014 - Jan. 2015

· Four exams passed with distinctioned related to EU law, Competiton Law, Commercial Law

Skills

Languages Italian: mother tongue. French: full professional proficiency. English: full professional proficiency

IT Skills Proficient in Microsoft Office Applications, GenDoc, Sysper

Legal Applications EurLex, LexisLibrary, DeJure, Lex24

Publications

- Research project organized by Roma Tre University (Prof. G. Rossi, Mario P. Chiti, G. Corso, Dian Schefold) in collaboration with the Italian Senate: "L'Unione Europea possibile e necessaria: l'Europa a cerchi concentrici"
- The determination of the object of the availment contract (avvalimento) in the public tender.

References_

Giovanni Pitruzzella Advocate General - Court of Justice of the European Union

Massimo Merola Managing Partner - Bonelli Erede Law Firm, Brussels office; Professor - College of Europe in Bruges, Belgium

Bernard Mongin Legal Advisor - European Commission's Legal Service; Ancien référendaire - Court of Justice of the European Union